cancercompass.com 2016-04-03

# Privacy Policy

Cancercompass® respects the privacy of its users.

Our goal is to provide you with a personalized Internet experience that delivers the information, and resources and services which are most relevant and helpful to you. To succeed in this aim, information is sometimes collected during your website visits to understand what differentiates you from each of our other users.

To demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we have prepared this statement disclosing the privacy practices for the entire Cancercompass.com website. Additional terms and conditions regarding the collection and use of your information may also be provided on Cancercompass® from time to time. This information may change without notice.

This document provides the following information: what information is collected and how it might be used, including personally identifiable data; how we protect the data we collect and who will have access to it; and how you can correct inaccurate information.

## What Information do we Collect?

Cancercompass® collects certain information from and about its users in two ways – directly from the User and from our Web server logs. None of the information that Cancercompass® collects is considered to be “protected health information” under HIPAA and its regulations, as this information is provided by you and is not gleaned from any medical records that are owned by any of our affiliates.

### Shared Data

Some of the information that Users provide about themselves may be shared with the Cancercompass® community, Partners, and others (“Shared Data”). Examples of Shared Data that users may submit on thewebsite, including through their health profile (“My Profile”), may include:

  * Biographical information, e.g. photograph, biography, gender, age, location (city, state and country), general notes;
  * Condition/disease information that you have self-reported, e.g. diagnosis date, first symptom, family history;
  * Treatment information that you have self-reported, e.g. treatment start dates, stop dates, dosages, side effects, treatment evaluations;
  * Symptom information that you have self-reported, e.g. severity, duration;
  * Individual and aggregated survey responses;
  * Information shared via free text fields, e.g. the forum, treatment evaluations, surveys, annotations, journals, feeds, adverse event reports; and
  * Connections to other people on the Site

In the course of using this site, Users may share information that could be used to reasonably identify themselves (“Personal Information”), including name, photograph, and email address. When a User voluntarily chooses to share Personal Information via a free text field (e.g. forum, treatment evaluations, annotations, journals, feeds and adverse event reports) and photos or images, the information will be treated as Shared Data.

### Links to other Website

Please note that if you use a link from our site to one of our partner's sites, our partner's use of any personal information collected from you during your use of that site, whether collected explicitly or automatically, will be governed by our partner's privacy policy, and not this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read our partner's online privacy policy, if available, or to contact the company directly about their privacy policy, before providing them with any personally-identifying information.

## Restricted Data

Some information that Users enter into certain fields when registering for or using this website will not be shared (“Restricted Data”). The type of Restricted Data that Users may submit could include:

  * Name, as collected as part of registration or in a Member’s Account Information;
  * Email address, as collected and verified as part of registration or in a Member’s Account Information;
  * Password, as collected as part of registration or in a Member’s Account Information;
  * Mailing address, as collected via email, forms, or private message
  * Date of birth, as collected in My Profile; and
  * Private messages.

When a User enters Personal Information, including name and email address, as part of registering to use Cancercompass®, that Personal Information is treated as Restricted Data.

### How Cancercompass.com uses your shared and restricted data

Users should expect that every piece of information they submit (even if it is not currently displayed), except for Restricted Data, might be shared with the community, other patients, and our Partners. Users are encouraged to share details of their health, but should consider that the more information entered, the more likely it is that a User could be located or identified.

There are instances where both Shared Data and Restricted Data, including Personal Information, may be used and disclosed. These include, but not limited to:

  * Cancercompass® uses both Shared Data and Restricted Data internally, as needed, for research, for maintenance and operation of the Site, and to create the best possible tools and functionality for patients.
  * In case of an emergency, Cancercompass® may use a User’s data to allow a member of the management team to directly contact the User.
  * Cancercompass® may share or disclose a User’s data where required by law or to comply with the legal process.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of data that often includes an anonymous, unique token, which is sent to your browser from a website’s computer and may be stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cancercompass.com uses two types of cookies:

  * Session Cookies are temporary and remain only until you log out of the website or close your browser. Session Cookies do not store any Personal Information, only a unique visitor ID number that may be used to ensure Users are properly authenticated and are able to view site information.
  * Persistent Cookies remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer, even after you leave the webiste. Persistent Cookies also do not store any Personal Information either. Instead, they store preferences that should persist from visit to visit; for example, “Remember Me,” and a unique token to enable us to understand how our Users utilize our website.

## Security Information:

When you visit an Internet website, you disclose certain information about yourself, such as your Internet [Protocol] (IP) address, the time of your visit, and the referring location (e.g., the Site or page that offered a link to a Cancercompass® page). Like many other websites, we keep track of the basic information about visits to our site. 

Please remember, whenever you voluntarily release personal information online, your information can be collected and used by others. Although Cancercompass® tries to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us – you do so at your own risk. 

Users are also solely responsible for keeping passwords and/or any account information confidential. Neither Cancercompass.com, Rising Tide,. nor Cancer Treatment Centers of America, Inc. is providing you with "covered health services" as such term is defined in HIPAA. For reasons described above and for other reasons, any information that you provide to Cancercompass.com will NOT be deemed in any way to be "protected health information", and as such, neither Cancercompass.com, Rising Tide. nor Cancer Treatment Centers of America, Inc. shall be obligated to deal with your information as required by HIPAA. By using this website, you acknowledge and agree that you will never assert against any of Cancercompass.com, Rising Tide, or Cancer Treatment Centers of America, Inc. any claims arising under HIPAA or its regulations.

## Web Server Logs:

This information helps us identify which areas of our site are of interest to visitors. Cancercompass® also collects the Internet [Protocol] (IP) addresses of its visitors for the purposes of system administration.

## Who Has Access to the Information?

Cancercompass® may disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or to protect the rights or property of Cancercompass®.

We welcome any questions or comments you have about the Cancercompass® site.

## How We Protect Your Information

Your personal data and its privacy and protection is crucial to us. Therefore, Cancercompass® does not pass on personal information to any third parties without your permission. This may or may not change in the future without notification. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective partners regarding your Cancercompass® usage are provided in aggregate form, which does not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user.

Your access to some services and content is password protected. It is never a good idea to reveal your password to anyone. Cancercompass® will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. If you are contacted for your user name or password, please do not share it.

Additionally, when applicable, you should always sign out of your Cancercompass® account or service at the end of each session. It is also good practice to close your browser window when you have finished your work. This ensures that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you are using a shared computer with someone else, or are working from a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

Unfortunately, no one can completely guarantee the security of data transmitted over the Internet. So, despite our efforts to protect personal data by using the latest security technology, Cancercompass® cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, or to or from our online products or services. All such information is submitted at your own risk. However, once a transmission is received, ensuring its safety and confidentiality on our systems are is of the highest priority.

 **Daily Operations:**  
Cancercompass.com   
1336 Basswood Road  
Schaumburg, IL 60173

 **Managed and Owned By:**  
Rising Tide, Kft.  
Herrenacker 15  
8200 Schaffhausen  
Switzerland
